Register of the Karl August Wittfogel papers, 1728-1992
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1907-1988.
  - Strzelewicz, Willy, 1961 (Folder 12)
  - Sudwestfunk, 1979-1981 (Folder 13)
  - SugarCo. Edizioni, 1964-1984 (Folder 14)
  - Suhrkamp Verlag (Raimund Fellinger, Siegfried Unseld), 1968-1985 (Folder 15)
  - Sumiya, Kazuhik, 1958-1959 (Folder 16)
  - Summers, Harry G., Jr., 1982 (Folder 17)
  - Sun, Yu-tang, 1948 (Folder 18)
  - Survey, 1950-1951 (Folder 19)
  - Suzuki, Jiro, 1958 (Folder 20)
  - Swadesh, Morris, 1960 (Folder 21)
  - Swann, Nancy Lee, 1940-1943 (Folder 22)
  - Symington, James W., 1971 (Folder 23)
  - Taiwan. Embassy (United States), 1958 (Folder 24)
  - Taiwan. Permanent Mission to the United Nations, 1955-1961 (Folder 25)
  - Talmedia, Onesimo, 1974 (Folder 26)
  - Tang, Peter S. H., 1955-1966 (Folder 27)
  - Tannenbaum, Frank, 1946-1947 (Folder 28)
  - Tao, Hsi-sheng, 1966-1967 (Folder 29)
  - Tao, L. K., 1935-1936 (Folder 30)
  - Tas, Sal, 1957 (Folder 31)
  - Tawney, R. H., 1934-1950 (Folder 32)
  - Tax, Sol, 1959 (Folder 33)
  - Taylor, Councill, 1959 (Folder 34)
  - Taylor, George E.
    - Undated (Folder 35)
    - 1935-1939 (Folder 36)
    - 1941-1949 (Box 45., Folder 1)
    - 1950-1952 (Folder 2)
    - 1953-1956 (Folder 3)
    - 1957-1958 (Folder 4)
    - 1959-1961 (Folder 5)
    - 1962-1969 (Box 46., Folder 1)
    - 1970-1978 (Folder 2)
    - 1981-1986 (Folder 3)
  - Taylor, Gordon T. C., 1969 (Folder 4)
  - Temple University, 1963 (Folder 5)
  - Teng, S. Y., 1958-1971 (Folder 6)
  - Thames and Hudson Ltd., 1957 (Folder 7)
  - Thayer, Peter J., 1973 (Folder 8)
  - Thiele, Ulrich and Julie, 1980-1984 (Folder 9)
  - Thomas, Norman, 1955 (Folder 10)
  - Thomas, Paul, 1966 (Folder 11)
  - Thomas Y. Crowell Co., 1959 (Folder 12)
  - Thompson, Charles, 1967 (Folder 13)
  - Thornton, Richard C., 1966-1969 (Folder 14)
  - Tiedemann, Arthur Everett, 1948 (Folder 15)
  - Tiedcke, Carl, 1958 (Folder 16)
  - Tietze, Andreas, 1979 (Folder 17)
  - Timberlake, Charles E., 1972 (Folder 18)
  - Tiro, Hasan M., 1955 (Folder 19)
  - Tobata, Seiichi, 1958-1961 (Folder 20)
  - Togan, Zeki Velidi, 1951-1961 (Folder 21)
  - Tokmakoff, George B., 1957-1961 (Folder 22)
  - Tokyo Shimbun, 1957 (Folder 23)
  - Tong, Te-kong, 1956-1967 (Folder 24)
  - Torii, Ryujiro, 1953-1955 (Folder 25)
  - Toynbee, Arnold J., 1947 (Folder 26)
  - Toyo Bunko (Oriental Library), 1949-1961 (Folder 27)
  - Trager, Frank N., 1967-1974 (Folder 28)
  - Transaction Publishers (Irving Louis Horowitz), 1983-1984 (Folder 29)
  - Treadgold, Donald W.
    - Undated (Folder 30)
    - 1954-1964 (Folder 31)
    - 1965-1984 (Box 47., Folder 1)
  - Treadgold, Warren, 1967-1977 (Folder 2)
  - Trebchen, A., 1977-1980 (Folder 3)
  - Trewartha, Glenn T., 1947-1950 (Folder 4)
  - Trobe University, 1970 (Folder 5)
  - Trommler, Frank, 1973 (Folder 6)
  - Trott, Harlan, 1960 (Folder 7)
  - Tsu, John B., 1963-1967 (Folder 8)
  - Tsuda, Sokichi, 1954 (Folder 9)
  - Tsui, Shu-chin, 1956-1958 (Folder 10)
  - Tucker, Robert, 1962 (Folder 11)
  - Tullock, Gordon, 1949-1967 (Folder 12)
  - Turney-High, Harry, 1960 (Folder 13)
  - U.K. Regional Information Office, 1966-1967 (Folder 14)
  - Ulam, Adam B., 1960-1965 (Folder 15)
  - Ulbert, Hans, 1947-1949 (Folder 16)
  - Ullstein Taschenbuchverlag, 1976-1979 (Folder 17)
  - Ulmen, Gary L.
    - Undated (Folder 18)
    - 1962-1965 (Folder 19)
    - 1966
      - January-May (Folder 20)
      - June-December (Folder 21)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 48., Folder 1)
    - 1970-1979 (Folder 2)
    - 1980-1984 (Folder 3)
  - Ulmen, Lee Roy, 1983 (Folder 4)
  - Ultimate Reality and Meaning, 1972-1980 (Folder 5)
  - Underhill, Ruth, 1947 (Folder 6)
  - Union Research Institute, 1956-1970 (Folder 7)
  - Union Theological Seminary, 1965-1967 (Folder 8)
  - United Citizens for Nixon-Agnew, 1968 (Folder 9)
  - United States. Congress. House of Representatives, 1954-1967 (Folder 10)
  - United States. Congress. House of Representatives. Committee on Un-American Activities, 1950-1960 (Folder 11)
  - United States. Congress. Senate, 1967 (Folder 12)
  - United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on the Judiciary. Subcommittee on Internal Security (Benjamin Mandel, Pat McCarran, Robert Morris, Julien G. Sourwine), 1951-1972 (Folder 13)
  - United States. Consulate (Hong Kong), 1958-1967. See also United States. Department of State (Folder 14)
  - United States. Department of Agriculture, 1965-1967 (Folder 15)
  - United States. Department of Commerce, 1972 (Folder 16)
  - United States. Department of Defense, 1968-1969 (Folder 17)
  - United States. Department of Justice (Leo A. Rover), 1953-1958 (Folder 18)
  - United States. Department of State, 1949-1957 (Folder 19)
  - United States. Department of State. Division of Exchange of Persons, 1950-1953 (Folder 20)
  - United States. Department of State. Division of External Research, 1957-1969 (Folder 21)
  - United States. Department of the Treasury. Internal Revenue Service, 1976 (Folder 22)
  - United States Information Agency, 1955-1967 (Folder 23)
  - Universal Book Company, 1958-1968 (Folder 24)
  - Universitat Hamburg, 1957 (Folder 25)
  - University Books, 1966 (Folder 26)
  - University of Adelaide, 1970 (Box 49., Folder 1)
  - University of Arizona (Bryant Bannister), 1961 (Folder 2)
  - University of Bombay (A. R. Desai, D. Narain), 1968-1972 (Folder 3)
  - University of California, 1969 (Folder 4)
  - University of Chattanooga (Jane Harbough), 1964-1965 (Folder 5)
  - University of Hong Kong (Ronald Hsia), 1959-1960 (Folder 6)
  - University of Kansas (George C. Anderson, Aldon D. Bell, Herbert Jay Ellison, Klaus H. Pringsheim), 1962-1963 (Folder 7)
  - University of Madras, 1971 (Folder 8)
  - University of Maryland, 1960 (Folder 9)
  - University of Melbourne (Frank Knopfelmacher, J. A. Thompson), 1970 (Folder 10)
  - University of Michigan (William Ballis), 1950-1961 (Folder 11)
  - University of Michigan Press, 1961-1968 (Folder 12)
  - University of Minnesota (John E. Turner), 1964 (Folder 13)
  - University of Nevada (Alex Simirenko), 1964-1965 (Folder 14)
  - University of New Castle, 1970 (Folder 15)
  - University of New South Wales, 1970 (Folder 16)
  - University of North Carolina (Roy N. Schantz), 1971-1972 (Folder 17)
  - University of Notre Dame (Waldemar Gurian), 1949 (Folder 18)
  - University of Oklahoma (Herbert Jay Ellison), 1960-1961 (Folder 19)
  - University of Pennsylvania (Bruce H. Dahlin), 1971-1972 (Folder 20)
  - University of Pennsylvania Press (Fred D. Wieck), 1970-1971 (Folder 21)
  - University of Sydney (Henry Mayer), 1970 (Folder 22)
  - University of Texas Press, 1972-1973 (Folder 23)
  - University of Washington
    - 1947-1948 (Folder 24)
    - 1949-1950 (Folder 25)
    - 1951-1956 (Folder 26)
    - 1957-1961 (Folder 27)
    - 1962-1967 (Box 50., Folder 1)
    - 1970-1979 (Folder 2)
  - University of Washington Libraries, 1948-1980 (Folder 3)
  - University of Washington Press (Donald R. Ellegood), 1966-1971 (Folder 4)
  - University of Wyoming, 1982 (Folder 5)
  - University Professors of Academic Order, 1971 (Folder 6)
  - Untermeyer, Chase, 1974-1984 (Folder 7)
  - Usami, Sediro, 1936? (Folder 8)
  - Utley, Freda, 1947 (Folder 9)
  - Vagts, Alfred, 1938-1980 (Folder 10)
  - Vanguard Press, 1961 (Folder 11)
  - Verlag Europaische Ideen (Andreas W. Mytze), 1970-1986 (Folder 12)
  - Verlag fur das Studium der Arbeiterbewegung, 1973 (Folder 13)
  - Verlag Kiepenheuer und Witsch, 1958-1981. Includes correspondence with Berend von Nottbeck (Verlag fur Politik und Wirtschaft) (Folder 14)
  - Verlag nach J. H. W. Dietz, 1957 (Folder 15)
  - Vernadsky, George, 1943 (Folder 16)
  - Verwilghen, Alb. Felix, 1964 (Folder 17)
  - Viereck, Peter, 1952 (Folder 18)
  - Viking Fund. See Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research
  - Vintage Books, 1981? (Folder 19)
  - Vittinghoff, Friedrich, 1961 (Folder 20)
  - Voegelin, Eric, 1963 (Folder 21)
  - Vogler, Ingeborg, 1970 (Folder 22)
  - Vogler, Paul, 1968-1969 (Box 51., Folder 1)
  - Vogt, Hans, 1963-1967 (Folder 2)
  - Volence, Helen and Vincent, 1963 (Folder 3)
  - Volksfront (Martin and Mary Hall), 1938 (Folder 4)
  - Vorwerk, Friedrich, 1956 (Folder 5)
  - WKCR Radio, 1962 (Folder 6)
  - W. Kohlhammer Verlag, 1956-1959 (Folder 7)
  - Wadekin, K., 1967 (Folder 8)
  - Walker, Richard L.
    - Undated (Folder 9)
    - 1951-1959 (Folder 10)
    - 1960-1985 (Folder 11)
  - Walter, Hilde, 1969 (Folder 12)
  - Walter-Verlag AG Olten, 1962 (Folder 13)
  - Wang, Anna L., 1956 (Folder 14)
  - Wang, Chi-wu, 1973 (Folder 15)
  - Wang, George, 1958 (Folder 16)
  - Wang, Yu-chuan, 1936-1937 (Folder 17)
  - Ward, A. W., 1966 (Box 52., Folder 1)
  - Ward, Lauriston, 1944-1952 (Folder 2)
  - Ware, James R., 1939-1949 (Folder 3)
  - Watanabe, Roo, 1958 (Folder 4)
  - Watnick, Morris, 1967 (Folder 5)
  - Way Forum, 1960 (Folder 6)
  - Weese, Berthold, 1957 (Folder 7)
  - Wegener, Agnes and Wilhelm, 1915-1951 (Folder 8)
  - Weigert, Hans W., 1957 (Folder 9)
  - Weil, Elsie, 1940 (Folder 10)
  - Weil, Felix J., 1947-1972 (Folder 11)
  - Weingarten, Adolph, 1962-1967 (Folder 12)
  - Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research, 1948-1959 (Folder 13)
  - Wernstrom, Milton H., 1968 (Folder 14)
  - Westdeutscher Rundfunk, 1977-1986 (Folder 15)
  - Westdeutscher Verlag, 1979 (Folder 16)
  - Westoby, Adam, 1981-1982 (Folder 17)
  - Weyl, Nathaniel, 1957 (Folder 18)
  - Wheeler, George E. and Rose, 1985 (Folder 19)
  - White, Lynn, Jr., 1943 (Folder 20)
  - White, William C., 1940-1948 (Folder 21)
  - White, William L., 1951-1957 (Folder 22)
  - Whitworth College, 1961-1962 (Folder 23)
  - Widtsoe, John A., 1947-1950 (Folder 24)
  - Wieck, Theresa, 1964 (Folder 25)
  - Wiggershaus, Rolf, 1979-1966 (Folder 26)
  - Wiggins, James W., 1962 (Folder 27)
  - Wilbur, C. Martin, 1941-1954 (Folder 28)
  - Wilder, Sean, 1985 (Folder 29)
  - Wilhelm, Hellmut, 1937-1972. Includes editorial comments on some of KAW's manuscripts (Folder 30)
  - Willert, Paul, 1957 (Folder 31)
  - William Volker Fund, 1956-1963 (Folder 32)
  - Willing, Peter and Kip, 1968 (Folder 33)
  - Williston, Frank G., 1966-1967 (Folder 34)
  - Wilson, David, 1972 (Folder 35)
  - Wimmelmann, Georg, 1946-1947 (Folder 36)
  - Wingenroth, Albert and Mathilde, 1970-1986 (Folder 37)
  - Wingenroth, El mar, 1969-1975 (Folder 38)
  - Winkler, Hartmut, 1957 (Box 53., Folder 1)
  - Wint, Guy, 1957 (Folder 2)
  - Winter, Ernst F., 1962 (Folder 3)
  - Wissenschaftliche Buchgesellschaft, 1957-1977 (Folder 4)
  - Wissmann, Hermann, 1956 (Folder 5)
  - Witsch, Kristian, 1975 (Folder 6)
  - Wittfogel, Dora and Heinrich, 1953-1963 (Folder 7)
  - Wittfogel, Erika and Hans, 1956 (Folder 8)
  - Wittfogel, Esther S.
    - 1941-1953 (Folder 9)
    - 1964 (Folder 10)
    - 1970-1972 (Folder 11)
  - Wittfogel, Gerda and Mimi
    - Undated (Folder 12)
    - 1935-1959 (Folder 13)
    - 1960-1982 (Folder 14)
  - Wittfogel, Heinz, Heidi, and Adelheid, 1949-1980 (Folder 15)
  - Wittfogel, Hermann, 1946-1949 (Folder 16)
  - Wittfogel, Johanne
    - Undated (Folder 17)
    - 1907-1912 (Folder 18)
    - 1913 (Folder 19)
    - 1914 (Folder 20)
    - 1915 (Folder 21)
    - 1916 (Box 54., Folder 1)
    - 1917
      - January-June (Folder 2)
      - July-December (Folder 3)
    - 1918 (Folder 4)
    - 1919 (Folder 5)
    - 1920-1921 (Folder 6)
    - 1924-1925 (Folder 7)
    - 1927 (Folder 8)
    - 1928 (Folder 9)
    - 1929 (Folder 10)
    - 1932 (Folder 11)
    - 1933 (Folder 12)
    - 1934
      - January-June (Folder 13)
      - July-December (Folder 14)
    - 1935 (Box 55., Folder 1)
    - 1936 (Folder 2)
    - 1937 (Folder 3)
    - 1938 (Folder 4)
    - 1940 (Folder 5)
    - 1941 (Folder 6)
  - Wittfogel, Katharina, 1948 (Folder 7)
  - Wittig, F., n.d. (Folder 8)
  - Wittig, Gunder K., 1978-1979 (Folder 9)
  - Wolf, Eric R., 1957-1982 (Folder 10)
  - Wolfe, Bertram D. and Ella, 1958-1976 (Folder 11)
  - Wolff, Ernst, 1961 (Folder 12)
  - Woloch, Isser and Elihu Richter, 1958 (Folder 13)
  - Woltman, Fred, 1950 (Folder 14)
  - Wong, David, 1985-1986 (Folder 15)
  - Woodburne, L. S., 1954 (Folder 16)
  - Woodbury, Richard B., 1957-1967 (Folder 17)
  - World Anti-Communist Congress for Freedom and Liberation (Charles Edison), 1958 (Folder 18)
  - World Politics, 1949-1961 (Folder 19)
  - World Youth Crusade for Freedom, 1973 (Folder 20)
  - Wright, Arthur F., 1949-1956 (Folder 21)
  - Wright, Arthur W., 1968 (Folder 22)
  - Wu, Cheng-tsu, 1958 (Folder 23)
  - Wu, Wen-tsao, 1938-1939 (Folder 24)
  - Wu, Y. L., 1963 (Folder 25)
  - Yale University Press
    - 1946 (Box 56., Folder 1)
    - 1955 (Folder 2)
    - 1956 (Folder 3)
    - 1957 (Folder 4)
    - 1958 (Folder 5)
    - 1959 (Folder 6)
    - 1960-1963 (Folder 7)
    - 1964-1988 (Folder 8)
  - Yang, C. K., 1948-1958 (Folder 9)
  - Yang, Lien-sheng, 1945 (Folder 10)
  - Yang, Martin M. C., 1955 (Folder 11)
  - Yao, Chia-chih, 1938-1947. Includes correspondence with Liu Yu-wan (Folder 12)
  - Yarmolinsky, Avrahm, 1969 (Folder 13)
  - Yee, Frank S. H., 1961 (Folder 14)
  - Yeh, George K. C., 1958-1959 (Folder 15)
  - Yeshiva College (Joseph Dunner), 1969-1974 (Folder 16)
  - Yetts, W. Perceval, 1947 (Folder 17)
  - Yokoyama, Suguru, 1958-1959 (Folder 18)
  - Yomiuri, 1954 (Folder 19)
  - Young, Thomas, 1969 (Folder 20)
  - Young Women's Christian Associations of China, 1938 (Folder 21)
  - Yuan, T. L., 1957 (Folder 22)
  - Zablocki, Clement J., 1965 (Folder 23)
  - Zaccone, June, 1960 (Folder 24)
  - Zaghi, Carlo, 1963-1964 (Folder 25)
  - Zeit, 1978 (Folder 26)
  - Zoffer, Gerald R., 1970 (Folder 27)
  - Zolbrod, Leon, 1956-1958 (Folder 28)
  - Zucker, Wolfgang M., 1964 (Folder 29)
- NOTES, n.d.
  - Miscellaneous (Box 57., Folder 1-12)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 58., Folder 1-7)
  - Aenisch, Erich (Folder 8)
  - Aboriginal Siberia (Folder 9)
  - Ancient Near East (Folder 10-13)
  - Ancient Near East and Japan (Folder 14)
  - Babylonia (Folder 15)
  - Baku (Folder 16)
  - Bali (Box 59., Folder 1)
  - Bauer, Bruno (Folder 2)
  - Byzantium (Folder 3)
  - Byzantium and Egypt (Folder 4)
  - China. Includes correspondence with Pedro Carrasco, Chang Chung-li, K. C. Hsiao, Marius B. Jansen, and Hellmut Wilhelm (Folder 5-16)
  - China (Box 60., Folder 1-8)
  - China and Japan (Folder 9)
  - Communist International (Comintern) (Folder 10)
  - Confiscation (taxes) (Folder 11)
  - Cotton (Folder 12)
  - Egypt (Box 61., Folder 1-2)
  - Eunuchs (Folder 3)
  - Hawaii (Folder 4)
  - Hydraulic societies (Folder 5)
  - Hydraulic works (Folder 6)
  - Hydraulics (Folder 7)
  - Incas (Folder 8)
  - India (Folder 9)
  - India, Japan, Indonesia, Hawaii, etc. (Folder 10)
  - Inprecorr (Folder 11)
  - Inscriptions (Box 62., Folder 1-2)
  - Islam (Folder 3)
  - Japan (Folder 4-6)
  - Kuo Mo-jo (Folder 7)
  - Kuomintang (Folder 8)
  - Li Li-san (Folder 9)
  - Madjar, Robert (Folder 10)
  - Mann, Thomas (Folder 11)
  - Marx, Karl (Folder 12)
  - Masai (Folder 13)
  - Mehring, Franz (Folder 14)
  - Mexico (Box 63., Folder 1-3)
  - Mormons (Folder 4)
  - Pelliot, Paul (Folder 5)
  - Pueblos (Folder 6)
  - Radek, Karl (Folder 7)
  - Russia (Folder 8-12)
  - Sicily (Folder 13)
  - Sumer (Folder 14)
  - Sun Yat-sen (Folder 15)
  - Theocracy (Folder 16)
  - Trotsky, Leon (Folder 17)
  - Turkey (Folder 18)
  - Viatkin (Folder 19)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1913-1990
  - Unidentified
    - Notes (Box 64., Folder 1-2)
    - Outlines (Folder 3)
    - Holograph
      - Loose sheets (Folder 4)
      - Fragments (Folder 5-10)
    - Typescript
      - Loose sheets (Folder 11-12)
      - Fragments (Folder 13-16)
  - "Analysis of Franz Borkenau's Memorandum on Sino-Soviet Relations," n.d. Typescript (Box 65., Folder 1)
  - "Aus diesem Herzen," n.d. Handwritten poem dedicated to Johanne Wittfogel (Folder 2)
  - "Autobiographical Notes," n.d.
    - General (Folder 3)
    - 'Needham' [Joseph] (Folder 4)
    - 1947-1951 ('Notes on Gary [Ulmen]'s Account of W[ittfogel]'s Russia Analysis and the Subsequent Development, Including W's 1951 Testimony') (Folder 5)
    - 1954-1956 (Folder 6)
    - 1957-1958 (Folder 7)
    - 1958 January (Folder 8)
  - "Chinese Revolution Reevaluated," n.d. Typescript (Folder 9)
  - "Climate and Seasonal Movements in China During the Second Millenium B.C. as Revealed Through the Divination Inscriptions of the Dynasty Shang," n.d. (Folder 10)
  - "Germany and Her Power," "Siegfried's Death," and "Jesus of Nazareth," n.d. Holographs (Folder 11)
  - "The Happiness of Country Life," n.d. Poem dedicated to Esther Wittfogel on her birthday. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - "Introduction of Anarchism to China," n.d. Notes and typescript outline (Folder 13)
  - "Karl Marx," n.d. Notes (Folder 14)
  - Notes on Pedro Armillas, Pedro Carrasco, and Angel R. Palerm, n.d. Includes writings by them, annotated by KAW (Folder 15)
  - "Notes on the Debate on the AMP," n.d. Holograph (Folder 16)
  - "The People's Tribune," n.d. Holograph (Folder 17)
  - "The Place of Southeast Asia in Moscow's Policy," n.d. Memorandum to George E. Taylor, head of the Far Eastern and Russian Institute, University of Washington, Seattle. Typescript (Folder 18)
  - "Preparatory Remarks," n.d. Typescript (Box 66., Folder 1)
  - "Problems of Oriental Despotism," n.d. Notes (Folder 2)
  - "Propaganda in Communist Controlled China," n.d. Typescript (Folder 3)
  - Reminiscences of the period 1922-1933, n.d. Typescript (in German) (Folder 4)
  - "Russia and the Open Historical Situation: Marxism, Anarchism, and the Asiatic Restoration," n.d. Holograph (Folder 5)
  - "Der Sekundaner: Eine Novelle," n.d. Typescript (Folder 6)
  - "A Short History of the Chinese Revolution," n.d. Typescript outline and first chapter (Folder 7)
  - "The Society of Prehistoric China," n.d. Typescript (Folder 8)
  - "The State and Foreign Policy," n.d. Holograph outline (Folder 9)
  - "The Third Weapon: A Study of Communist Strategy and Ideology," n.d. Typescript outline (Folder 10)
  - "Trotsky und Stalin," n.d. Holograph (Folder 11)
  - "Warum habe ich die Gegenaktion gegen den sogenannten Friedenskongress in New York unterstuzt? Ich war doch fruher einmal ein aktiver Freund der Sowjetunion," n.d. Typescript (Folder 12)
  - "Fruhe Schriften," 1913-1915. Holograph essays, fairytales, and plays
    - I (1913-1914) (Box 67., Folder 1)
    - II (1915) (Folder 2)
    - III (Folder 3)
    - IV (Folder 4)
    - V (Folder 5)
    - VI (Folder 6)
    - VII (Folder 7)
    - VIII ("Rurick," 1915) (Folder 8)
    - IX (Folder 9)
    - X (Folder 10)
    - XI (Folder 11)
    - XII ("Der Lilagotze," 1914) (Folder 12)
  - "Lied," 1914 April 16. Handwritten poem (Folder 13)
  - Notes on Theodor Fontane, 1914-1915. Holograph (Folder 14)
  - "Ibsen oder Strindberg," 1915 December. Typescript (Folder 15)
  - "Die Marschrichtung des Lebens," Freideutsche Jugend, 1917 July. Printed copy (Folder 16)
  - Six speeches on Chinese poetry, wisdom, and belief, Berlin, Germany, 1919 June-August. Announcements and clippings (Folder 17)
  - Die Wissenschaft der burgerlichen Gesellschaft: Eine marxistische Untersuchung, 1922
    - Printed copy (pirated edition) (Folder 18)
    - Review (Folder 19)
  - "Dostojewski und der Bolschewismus," Vivos Voco, 1922 June. Printed copy (Folder 20)
  - "Der Heilige, der Abenteurer und der Held: Bemerkungen zur Krise des europaischen Idealismus," Politischer Rundbrief: "Zum hohen Meissner," 1923. Printed copy (Folder 21)
  - "Lenin oder Mussolini?" Politischer Rundbrief: "Durch Kampfgemeinschaft zur Volksgemeinschaft," 1923. Printed copy (Folder 22)
  - Wer Ist der Dummste?1923. Program (of play production) and clippings (Folder 23)
  - Geschichte der burgerlichen Gesellschaft: Von ihren Anfangen bis zur Schwelle der grossen Revolution, 1924. See also CORRESPONDENCE, SOAK-Verlag
    - Review (Folder 24)
    - 1977 edition, with new dedication, introduction, and biographical note
      - General (Folder 25)
      - Notes (Folder 26)
      - Typescript and proofs (Folder 27)
  - Das erwachende China, 1926. Reviews (Folder 28)
  - "Grundelemente der okonomisch (sic) sozialen Entwicklung Chinas," 1927. Outline of projected book (Wirtschaft und Gesellschaft Chinas?). Typescript (Folder 29)
  - "Probleme der chinesischen Wirtschaftsgeschichte," Archiv fur Sozialwissenschaft, 1927. Printed copy of Russian translation (Folder 30)
  - "Viertausend Jahre chinesische (sic) Wirtschafts- und Sozialgeschichte," 1927. Outline of projected book (Wirtschaft und Gesellschaft Chinas?). Typescript (Folder 31)
  - "Die okonomische Bedeutung der agrikolen und industriellen Produktivkrafte Chinas," 1928. Title page, dedication, table of contents, and bibliography of printed copy of dissertation, published in 1930 (Folder 32)
  - "Geopolitik, geographischer Materialismus und Marxismus," Unter dem Banner des Marxismus, 1929. See also CORRESPONDENCE, Wissenschaftliche Buchgesellschaft
    - Printed copy (Folder 33)
    - 1977 edition, with new foreword
      - Typescript (Folder 34)
      - Proofs (Folder 35)
      - Printed copy (Folder 36)
    - English translation. Holograph fragments. See also CORRESPONDENCE, Peet, Richard (Folder 37)
  - "Zur Frage einer marxistischen Asthetik," Linkskurve, 1930-1932 (series of seven articles, some with a slightly modified title). See also CORRESPONDENCE, Verlag Europaische Ideen
    - General (Box 68., Folder 1)
    - Pirated edition, Asthetik und Kommunikation, 1970 December. Printed copy (Folder 2)
    - Reprint published by Kolnkalkverlag, 1973 March. Printed copy (Folder 3)
    - New authorized edition, entitled Beitrage zur marxistischen Asthetik, 1977
      - Typescript of afterword originally written on 1971 June 14 for a never materialized publication with Luchterhand Verlag (Folder 4)
      - Printed copy (Folder 5)
      - Reviews (Folder 6)
      - English translation, including introduction by translator Dorothy Rosenberg and afterword annotated by KAW in 1977. Typescript. Includes letter by Ronald Reimers (Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, 1971-1978 (Folder 8)
  - "Geschichtsentwicklung und Revolution in Hegels Philosophie," 1931. Typescript (Folder 9-10)
  - Wirtschaft und Gesellschaft Chinas: Versuch der wissenschaftlichen Analyse einer grossen asiatischen Agrargesellschaft, 1931
    - Typescript of projected second volume (never published as such) (Box 69., Folder 1-2)
    - Reviews (Folder 3)
    - Japanese translation. Typescript of foreword to 2nd edition, 1936 May 9 (Folder 4)
    - Spanish translation. Correspondence, 1981 (Folder 5)
  - "Entwicklungsstufen und Wirkungskraft proletarisch- revolutionarer Kulturarbeit," Linkskurve, 1931 January. Printed copy (Folder 6)
  - "Wissen und Gesellschaft," Unter dem Banner des Marxismus, 1931 February. Review of five books. Printed copy (Folder 7)
  - "Der Faschismus 'beerbt' Hegel," Linkskurve, 1931 November. Printed copy (Folder 8)
  - "Hegel uber China," Unter dem Banner des Marxismus, 1931 December. Printed copy (Folder 9)
  - "Die Entstehung des Staates nach Marx und Engels," in Festschrift fur Carl Grunberg zum 70. Geburtstag, 1932. Printed copy (Folder 10)
  - "Goethe: Deutschlands grosster Dichter - Ein Opfer der deutschen 'Misere,'" Rote Fahne, 1932 March 22. Printed copy (Box 70.)
  - "Adolf Hitlers wahre 'Grosse': Versuch eines sozialpsychologischen Portrats," Rote Fahne, 1933 February 4. Printed copy (Box 71., Folder 1)
  - Notes, British Museum, London, England, 1934 January 9-March 10. Holograph (Folder 2)
  - "The Foundations and Stages of Chinese Economic History," Zeitschrift fur Sozialforschung, 1935 (originally written in German but translated and first published in English)
    - Typescript (unabridged German version) (Folder 3)
    - Printed copy (Folder 4)
    - Slightly condensed version, minus footnotes. Typescript (in English) (Folder 5)